<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Ecological Network</title>
    <link>//localhost:4321/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Ecological Network</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:4321/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/content/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:4321/content/research/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/note/2025/02/15/a-quick-note/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:4321/note/2025/02/15/a-quick-note/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/note/2025/02/15/another-note/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:4321/note/2025/02/15/another-note/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CV</title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:4321/cv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Education&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2019.06 &amp;ndash; 2020.07 Ph.D study in the Ecology at University of Freiburg, Germany&#xA;(supported by a fellowship of the UCAS, cooperate with Dr. &lt;a href=&#34;https://jochenfruend.wordpress.com&#34;&gt;Jochen Fründ&lt;/a&gt; at&#xA;Prof. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.biom.uni-freiburg.de/mitarbeiter/dormann&#34;&gt;Carsten Dormann&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s Biometry and Environmental System Analysis group)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2017.09 &amp;ndash; 2021.01: Ph.D., Ecology, at the Institute of Zoology, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing, China (Supervisor: Prof. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Xiao-Zhishu&#34;&gt;Zhishu Xiao&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2012.09 &amp;ndash; 2016.01: M.S., Botany, Kunming Institute of Botany, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Kunming, China (Supervisor: Prof. &lt;a href=&#34;http://groups.english.kib.cas.cn/klpb/wh/&#34;&gt;Hong Wang&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2008.09 &amp;ndash; 2012.07: B.S., Biological Science, Yunnan University, Kunming, China.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work Experience&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ecological Network</title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:4321/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:4321/img/frugivory2.png&#34; alt=&#34;frugivory&#34;&gt;&#xA;My name is Hai-Dong Li, Associate Professor at KIB, I am interested in understanding any type of biotic interactions&#xA;in our changing world.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How the biodiversity shaped on Earth? Darwin had stated that the evolution of biodiversity&#xA;on earth involved two aspects: species diversity and the interactions diversity.&#xA;But how inter-specific interactions shaped the biodiversity?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:4321/publications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Papers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;2024&#34;&gt;2024&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Li HD. 2024. BiMultiNetPlot: An R package for visualizing ecological bipartite multilayer networks. bioRxiv, 2024-09.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;2023&#34;&gt;2023&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Li HD, Holyoak M, Xiao ZS*. 2023. Disentangling spatiotemporal dynamics in metacommunities through a species-patch network approach. Ecology Letters. 26: 1261-1276.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Li HD, Tang LF, Jia CX, Holyoak M, Fründ J, Huang XQ, Xiao ZS*. 2023. Considering vertical space reveals hidden links and increased modularity of plant–frugivore networks, OIKOS. 2023: e09327.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ji C, Li HD, Xiao W, Xu K, Ren Y, Li H, Wang P, Fan M, Huang X, Xiao Z. Fine-Scale Interactions between Leopard Cats and Their Potential Prey with Contrasting Diel Activities in a Livestock-Dominated Nature Reserve. Animals. 2023; 13(8):1296.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;2022&#34;&gt;2022&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sun X#, Li HD#, Zhang A, Hirka A, Csóka G, Pearse I, Holyoak M, Xiao ZS*. 2022. An intercontinental comparison of insect seed predation between introduced and native oaks. Integrative Zoology, 17(2): 217-230 (co-first author)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Zhao YH, Lázaro A, Li HD, Tao ZB, Liang H, Zhou W, Ren ZX, Xu K, Li DZ, Wang H. 2022. Morphological trait-matching in plant–Hymenoptera and plant–Diptera mutualisms across an elevational gradient. Journal of Animal Ecology, 91(1): 196-209. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/1365-2656.13614&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/1365-2656.13614&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;2021&#34;&gt;2021&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;李海东, 吴新卫, 肖治术. 2021. 种间互作网络的结构、生态系统功能及稳定性机制研究. 植物生态学报. 45(10): 1049-1063&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Liang H, Zhao YH, Rafferty N, Ren ZX, Zhong L, Li HD, Li DZ, Wang H. 2021. Evolutionary and ecological processes influence a plant-bumble bee network: abundance and nectar shape phylogenetic attraction patterns. Functional Ecology, 35(11): 2523-2535.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Zhao YH, Memmott J, Vaughan I, Li HD, Ren ZX, Lazaro A, Zhou W, Xu X, Wang WJ, Liang H, Li DZ, Wang H. 2021. The impact of a native dominant plant, Euphorbia jolkinii, on plant-flower visitor networks and plant reproductive success in sub-alpine meadows of Shangri-La, SW China. Journal of Ecology, 109(5): 2107-2120&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;2020&#34;&gt;2020&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Li HD, Tang L, Jia C, Holyoak M, Fründ J, Huang X, Xiao ZS*. 2020. The functional roles of species in metacommunities, as revealed by metanetwork analyses of bird–plant frugivory networks. Ecology Letters. 23: 1252-1262.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;2019&#34;&gt;2019&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tang H, Hood ME, Ren ZX, Li DZ, Li HD, Zhao YH, Wolfe LM, Wang H*. 2019. Specificity and seasonal prevalence of anther-smut disease on sympatric Himalayan Silene species. Journal of Evolutionary Biology. 32: 451-462. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/jeb.13427&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/jeb.13427&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Zhao YH, Lázaro A, Ren ZX, Zhou W, Li HD, Tao ZB, Xu K, Wu ZK, Wolfe LM, Li DZ, Wang H*. 2019. The topological differences between visitation and pollen transport networks: a comparison in species rich communities of the Himalaya-Hengduan Mountains. Oikos. 128: 551-562. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/oik.05262&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/oik.05262&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ren ZX, Bernhardt P, Edens-Meier R, Zweck J, Arduser M, Li HD, Wang H*. 2019. Comparative Pollen-Pistil Interactions and Insect-Pollination in Two Hypoxis Species (Hypoxidaceae) in China and North America. Plant Systematics and Evolution. 305: 115-126. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s00606-018-1556-6&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s00606-018-1556-6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;2018&#34;&gt;2018&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Li HD, Ren ZX, Zhou W, Bernhardt P, Zhao YH, Wu ZK, Li DZ, Wang H*. 2018. Comparative intra-and inter-specific sexual organ reciprocity in four distylous Primula species in the Himalaya-Hengduan Mountains. Plant Biology. 20: 643-653.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tao ZB, Ren ZX*, Bernhardt P, Wang WJ, Liang H, Li HD, Wang H*. 2018. Nocturnal hawkmoth and moth pollination of Habenaria limprichtii Schltr. (Orchidaceae) in sub-alpine meadows of the Yulong Snow Mountain (Yunnan, China). Botanical Journal of the Linnean Society. 187: 483-498. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1093/botlinnean/boy023&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1093/botlinnean/boy023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tao ZB, Ren ZX*, Bernhardt P, Liang H, Li HD, Zhao YH, Wang H*, Li DZ. 2018. Does reproductive isolation reflect the segregation of color forms in the Spiranthes sinensis (Pers.) Ames complex (Orchidaceae) in the Chinese Himalayas? Ecology and Evolution. 8: 5455-5469. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/ece3.4067&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/ece3.4067&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;2017&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Li HD, Zhao YH, Ren ZX, Wu ZK, Wolfe LM, Bernhardt P, Wang H*. 2017. Fitness-related selection on floral traits in the distylous plant Primula poissonii (Primulaceae). Journal of Plant Ecology. 10(3): 559-568.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Zhou W, Barrett, SCH, Li HD, Wu Z K, Wang XJ, Wang H, Li DZ*. 2017. Phylogeographic insights on the evolutionary breakdown of heterostyly. New Phytologist. 214: 1368–1380. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/nph.14453&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1111/nph.14453&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;2016&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Zhao YH, Ren ZX, Lázaro A, Wang H*, Bernhardt P, Li HD, Li DZ*. 2016. Floral traits and plant specialization at different communities of the Himalaya-Hengduan Mountains. BMC Ecology. 16: 26.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Zhou W, Li HD, Wu ZK, Spencer B, Li DZ, Wang H*. 2016. Characterization of 24 microsatellite markers in Primula chungensis (Primulaceae), a distylous-homostylous species, using MiSeq sequencing. Plant Diversity. 38(2): 110-113.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;2015&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;李海东, 任宗昕, 吴之坤, 许坤; 王红. 2015. 二型花柱植物海仙花报春花部性状随地理梯度的变异. 生物多样性: 23(6): 747-758.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Book Chapters&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:4321/research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ecological network vary across time and space&lt;/strong&gt;   &lt;br&gt;&#xA;My research explores the dynamic changes of ecological networks in space and time and&#xA;its impact on biodiversity and ecosystem function. Using pollination and seed dispersal&#xA;networks as model systems, I am committed to analyzing how ecological networks&#xA;respond to natural environmental gradients (e.g., altitude, habitat diversity)&#xA;and human-driven environmental changes (e.g., forest fragmentation and climate change),&#xA;and to deeply examine the temporal dynamics of ecological networks (e.g., seasonal dynamics).&#xA;My research objective is to reveal the relationship between ecological network&#xA;structure and function, and their response mechanisms to environmental change,&#xA;thereby providing a theoretical foundation for biodiversity conservation and&#xA;sustainable ecosystem management.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
